Guide to the Sara and Gerald Murphy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material, 1932-1999; Series VI; 1.21 linear feet (5 boxes)
  - Home Movies
    - Films
      - "Person sleeping and dog." One 16mm reel, 30 feet, roughly 0.50 minutes, undated (Box 196 (Cold storage))
      - "Boys playing baseball (F.S. on sweatshirt) and baby girl." Two 8mm reels, 50 feet, roughly 3.42 minutes each, undated (Box 195 (Cold storage))
      - "Mr. W. Donnelly." One 16mm reel, 300 feet, roughly 8.20 minutes, undated (Box 197 (Cold storage))
      - "Nothing." One 16mm reel, 30 feet, roughly 0.50 minutes, undated (Box 198 (Cold storage))
    - Original housings (Box 205–206)
      The materials are open for research.
      Box 205: original housings
      "X-mas Conway, Bedford Coasting, Small Shots of Boat."
      "Sailing Weatherbird."
      "First Spanish Trip."
      "Second Spanish Trip."
      "Saranac Lake."
      "Summer 1938."
      "Swan Cove."
      "Bad parts."
      "Weatherbird – Corsica and Monte Carlo."
      "East Hampton, Honoria, Noël [Haskins Murphy]."
      "East Hampton, Honoria, Alan [Jarvis?], Lloyd [Bowers?], puppies, Gerald, Barrys."
      "Best picture of puppies, Alan [Jarvis?], Fanny [Brennan Myers]."
      "Roll with Susan."
      "Louise [Dowdney], Honoria, puppies."
      Box 206: original housings
      "Puppies, chrysanthemums, Virginia Lake."
      "Puppies."
      "New puppies and Pomona in all forms."
      Unidentified.
      "H.M. Donnelly and W.M. Donnelly, Rushes Pictures."
      "Mr. W. Donnelly, synchronized sound, double system."
      "Boy ice skating."
      "Boy sailing sloops in lake."
      "Person sleeping and dog."
      "Boys playing baseball (F.S. on sweatshirt) and baby girl."
      "Mr. W. Donnelly."
      "Nothing."
  - Recordings Created and Collected by Honoria Donnelly
    - Sound Recordings
      - "Ernestine [Leray] describing 'Villa America'", 1978 October 14; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974213)
        Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - "Ernestine [Leray] 'At Home' in Gael", 1981 June 16; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974205)
        A written note reads: [Ernestine] cooked a frozen chicken for us with [?] and wine. Beautiful country and [?] trip - train there, plane back
      - "Aunt Noël [Haskins Murphy] in Orgeval and in Playa Modellino, original", 1981 June 9 and 17; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974171)
      - "Aunt Noël [Haskins Murphy] in Orgeval, Ditto except for last few minutes which is a few minutes of coffee at Place Modellino from our room", 1981 June 9 and 17; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974197)
      - "Aunt Noël [Haskins Murphy] in Orgeval, original, 2nd tape", 1981 June 10; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974189)
      - "Bayonne -- at #38 Rue Herrelle -- Looking at photos and letters. We can take them all home, copy what we wish, and return the rest. She wants them to be buried with her!" (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1981 June 13-14; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974221)
      - "Bayonne" / "Mamzelle, Bayonne", undated; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974239)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
      - "Mamzelle, Bayonne", 1981 June 14; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974247)
      - "Jacques Livet and Simone Labrousse in Mad-Plaza", 1981 June 19; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974254)
      - "Hester [Pickman]" (1 of 5 audiocassettes), 1981 July 7-9; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974270)
      - "Hester Pickman and David, Betsy, Daisy" (2 of 5 audiocassettes), 1981 July 8; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974288)
      - "2nd eve at Hester's, David - there's some left" (3 of 5 audiocassettes), 1981 July 9; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974262)
      - "Pickmans" (4 of 5 audiocassettes), 1981 July 8; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974296)
      - Lunch at Daisy's, Hester Pickman (5 of 5 audiocassettes), 1981 July 9; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974304)
      - "Practice Archive Interview" (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1982 February; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974312)
      - "Practice" (2 of 3 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974320)
      - "Practice Archive Interview" (3 of 3 audiocassettes), 1982 February; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974338)
      - "Donnelly / NPR, ATC, ME" (audiocassette), 1983 January 31, March 10; 1 (Box 93, Item barcode 39002109974346)
      - "Honoria Murphy Donnelly" (audiocassette), 1983 March 8; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974007)
      - "An Informal Hour with Dorothy Parker, Read by Dorothy Parker", reading from her poems and "Horse" (audiocassette), 1983; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974015)
        A list of poems on this audiocassette is included.
        The Lady's Reward
        Plea
        The Red Dress
        The Little Old Lady
        One Perfect Rose
        The Veteran
        Parable of a Certain Virgin
        Tombstones
        The Evening Primrose
        Afternoon
        The Burned Child
        The False Friends
        The Satin Dress
        Recurrence
        Inscription for the Ceiling of a Bedroom
        To Newcastle
        Men
        For an Unknown Lady
      - "WJNO Interviews Recorded at Palm Beach Ocean Hotel" (audiocassette), 1984 March 12; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974023)
      - "Russian Tea Room" (audiocassette), 1991 June 6; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974031)
        A handwritten note from Mary Erit reads: Enclosed is the cassette tape of "Parsley till the Train Leaves". Enjoy!
      - "'Easy to Love,' A Cole Porter 100th Birthday Tribute" (1 of 2 audiocassettes) and note from Jeff Lunden, 1991; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974049)
      - "'Easy to Love,' A Cole Porter 100th Birthday Tribute" (2 of 2 audiocassettes) and note from Jeff Lunden, 1991; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974056)
      - "Steve Ross's Music", Porter orch. (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1993; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974064)
        A note included with this audiocassette from October 8th reads: Dear Honoria, I feel fortunate to have had you all to myself for even those few moments this week. I hope I didn't go on and on about the ups and downs of this troubadour's emotional life. You were very sweet and understanding but I do get carried away from time to time. Thank God I have the ventilation of those wonderful songs or I would be intolerable company, I fear. I hope you enjoy the cassettes. I shall think of you on your amazing terrace listening to them and be very happy if they bring you pleasure. Love, Steve
      - "Steve Ross's Music", Talents to Amuse (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1993 August 6; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974072)
      - "Fanny Brennan and Honoria M. Donnelly on Charlie Finch on WBAI" (audiocassette), 1994 December 1; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974080)
      - "L. Hellman II & I" (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974098)
      - L. Hellman III & IV?, undated; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974106)
      - "Honoria and Dick Re: Spence and Trips to Saranac" (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1981 June 26; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974114)
      - "Honoria and Dick Re: Spence and Trips to Saranac" (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1981 June 26; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974122)
      - "First half is beginning of reading scrapbooks with a few minutes with Foley's then back to books" (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974130)
      - "Prince George Hotel, Tony Randall" / "A Christmas Tree" (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974148)
      - "Donnelly" (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974155)
      - "T-120 original" (audiocassette), undated; 1 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002109974163)
      - "Tape 1", undated; 1 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002109973959)
      - "Tape 2", undated; 1 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002109973967)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002109973975)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002109973983)
    - Video Recordings
      - "WJLA Channel 7 in Washington, D.C. Interview at Omaha", 1984-06-05-1984-06-06; YCALMSS468_0001; 1; 00:03:45 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310670)
      - "Hemingway" 1 of 4, 1988 September 1; YCALMSS468_0002; 1; 01:02:16; NTSC (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310688)
      - "Hemingway" 2 of 4, 1988 September 1; YCALMSS468_0003; 1; 01:01:00; NTSC (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310696)
      - "Hemingway" 3 of 4, 1988 September 1; YCALMSS468_0004; 1; 01:02:12; NTSC (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310704)
      - "Hemingway" 4 of 4, 1988 September 1; YCALMSS468_0005; 1; 01:01:57 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310712)
      - "CBS This Morning, Small Paintings", 1990 October 1; YCALMSS468_0006; 1; 00:05:21 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310720)
      - "The Odyssey of John Dos Passos", 1993; YCALMSS468_0007; 1; 01:00:22 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310738)
      - "Mrs. Francis Brennan, Mrs. William Donnelly, Paris Show", 1994 July 5; YCALMSS468_0008; 1; 01:20:19 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310746)
      - "Sunday Morning, Picasso at MOMA with portraits of S.M. [Sara Murphy]", 1996 May 5; YCALMSS468_0009; 1; 00:17:14 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310753)
      - "The Phillips Collection: Slide Lecture 'Stories of Villa America and the Lost Generation,' Speakers: Dr. Linda Patterson Miller, Fannie Brennan, and Honoria Donnelly" 1 of 3, 1996 May 14; YCALMSS468_0010; 1; 01:08:28 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310761)
      - "The Phillips Collection: Slide Lecture 'Stories of Villa America and the Lost Generation,' Speakers: Dr. Linda Patterson Miller, Fannie Brennan, and Honoria Donnelly" 2 of 3, 1996 May 14; YCALMSS468_0011; 1; 01:12:36 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310779)
      - "The Phillips Collection: Slide Lecture 'Stories of Villa America and the Lost Generation,' Speakers: Dr. Linda Patterson Miller, Fannie Brennan, and Honoria Donnelly" 3 of 3, 1996 May 14; YCALMSS468_0012; 1; 01:11:54 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310787)
      - "Lost Generation Dinner", 1996 June 10; YCALMSS468_0013; 1; 00:59:31 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310795)
        The tape also reads: [Laura's] friend - Japanese chef.
      - "AMIP, Scott Fitzgerald, VF St. Francais" and note from Jean Francois Vallee (of French Television), 1996; YCALMSS468_0014; 1; 00:51:06 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310803)
        Some type of French article on F. Scott Fitzgerald is included with the tape. A typed letter is also included. It reads: Dear Honoria, Here is the promised copy and two main reviews. I hope you will like it. Let me know. Thank you again for your precious help. I look forward to talk to you soon. JFV (Jean Francois Vallee)
      - "F. Scott Fitzgerald Lecture", 1998 March 2; YCALMSS468_0015; 1; 01:39:20; There are 19 minutes of 'snow' at the end. (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310811)
      - "H.M.D. Interview for BBC re: F. Scott Fitzgerald", undated; YCALMSS468_0016; 1; 00:55:27 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310829)
      - "Zelda", undated; 1; 03:16:13; The last episode of the TV show "Cheers" airs after the film. (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310837)
      - "Avanti Prods., 'Hemingway Home Movies,' Camera Rolls: 1-3", 1999-08-10; YCALMSS468_0018; 1; 00:25:45 (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310845)
      - Untitled, undated; YCALMSS468_0019; 1; This video has not been digitized. There was sound of an old film and picture was snowy throughout. (Box 97, Item barcode 39002102310852)
      - Untitled, undated; YCALMSS468_0020; 1; 01:19:59 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102310860)
- Honoria Murphy Donnelly Papers, 1925-2003; Series VII; 5.84 linear feet (15 boxes)
  The series is organized into five subseries: Correspondence, Diaries and Notebooks, Other Papers, Writings, and Printed Materials.
  The series documents Honoria Murphy Donnelly's early life and later work to ensure the legacy of her parents and their friends. The Correspondence subseries contains Donnelly's exchanges with family friends, such Archibald MacLeish, while researching her books. The Murphys' connection to a number of authors and artists also resulted in Donnelly's role in providing interviews and facilitating researchers' access to her family's extensive archive, evidence of which can also be found in the Correspondence subseries. The resurgence of interest in Gerald Murphy's artwork is apparent in Donnelly's correspondence with various galleries and curators, in addition to several exhibition catalogues (located in the Printed Materials subseries).
  Donnelly's diaries and notebooks, dating from 1927 to 1948, provide evidence of her family's excursions and way of life, such as their trip to Montana with Hemingway and sailing trips. The Other Papers subseries includes juvenilia as well as material relating to Donnelly's marriages and family life as an adult.
  The Writings subseries consists of research notes, drafts, and other material that captures Donnelly's work towards her book, Sara & Gerald, in which she chronicles her parents and childhood, and her unpublished project Villa America Cookbook.
  The Printed Materials subseries is comprised of Donnelly's collection of clipping files which document the Murphys as well as family friends.
  - Correspondence
    - "A" general, 1974 February 10 (Box 98, Folder 963)
    - Allen, Jay, 1982 January 7 (Box 98, Folder 964)
    - "B" general, 1997 December 8 (Box 98, Folder 965)
    - Baker, Carlos, 1980, 1982 (Box 98, Folder 966)
    - Benchley, Robert, 1983-1984 (Box 98, Folder 967)
    - Brackett, Charles and Elizabeth, 1983 February 9 (Box 98, Folder 968)
    - Brooks, John, 1971, 1982 (Box 98, Folder 969)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew J. (Matthew Joseph), 1974 October 26 (Box 98, Folder 970)
    - "C" general, 1934 January and 1995 (Box 98, Folder 971)
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick, 1935-1939, undated (Box 98, Folder 972-973)
    - Carr, Virginia Spencer, 1977 (Box 98, Folder 974)
    - Christie's, 2000 October (Box 98, Folder 975)
    - Clark, C.E. Frazer, 1972 (Box 98, Folder 976)
    - Donnelly, John, 1985 November 6, 2000 (Box 98, Folder 977)
      Includes letter to John Donnelly from Winston Conrad and an aerial view of East Hampton
    - Dos Passos family (John, Betty, and Lucy), 1950-1984, undated (Box 98, Folder 978-980)
    - Dos Passos, Katharine, 1935-1947, undated (Box 98, Folder 981-983)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1935-1940 (Box 98, Folder 984-985)
      General note
      Copies of letters addressed to Gerald and Sara Murphy
    - Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1940, 1945 (Box 99, Folder 986)
    - "G" general, 1976 January 3 (Box 99, Folder 987)
    - Geŕon, Henriette "Mamzelle", 1977-1983 (Box 99, Folder 988)
    - Gielgud, John, 1937, 1939, undated (Box 99, Folder 989)
    - Greenman, Frances Cranmer, 1973-1978 (Box 99, Folder 990)
    - "H" general, 1976-1980 (Box 99, Folder 991)
    - Hill, Patrick, 1942-1981 (Box 99, Folder 992)
    - HG Magazine, 1991, undated (Box 99, Folder 993)
    - "L" general, 1983 February 7 (Box 99, Folder 994)
    - Léger, Fernand, 1965-1984 (Box 99, Folder 995)
    - Leray, Ernestine, 1935-1981 (Box 99, Folder 996)
    - Library of Congress, 1974-1981 (Box 99, Folder 997)
    - Livet, Jacques E., 1981 (Box 99, Folder 998)
      Includes reminiscence "La Premiere Croisiere de Gerald ou L'Initiation a la Mer"
    - Lowndes, Lloyd "Diddy", 1941-1981 (Box 99, Folder 999)
    - "M" general, 1965-1984 (Box 99, Folder 1000)
    - MacLeish, Ada, 1969-1980, undated (Box 99, Folder 1001-1002)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1967-1982 (Box 99, Folder 1003)
    - Mark Cross Company, 1991-1992 (Box 99, Folder 1004)
    - Murphy, Gerald and Sara, 1933, 1962-1963, undated (Box 99, Folder 1005)
    - Musée national Fernand Léger, 1998 (Box 99, Folder 1006)
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1974, 1996-1997 (Box 99, Folder 1007)
    - Museum correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 100, Folder 1008-1009)
    - National Portrait Gallery (Smithsonian Institution), 1980 (Box 100, Folder 1010)
    - "P" general, 1981 May 7 (Box 100, Folder 1011)
    - Parker, Dorothy and Alan Campbell, 1979-1982 (Box 100, Folder 1012)
    - Phillips Collection, 1994-1997 (Box 100, Folder 1013)
    - Porter, Cole, 1946, 1974-1983 (Box 100, Folder 1014-1015)
    - "R" general, 1972, 1982 (Box 100, Folder 1016)
    - Randall, Tony, 1982, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 1017)
    - "S" general, 1980, 2002 (Box 100, Folder 1018)
    - Short, Bobby, 1984 October 22 (Box 100, Folder 1019)
    - Smith, Scottie Fitzgerald, 1967-1988, undated (Box 100, Folder 1020-1021)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 1022)
    - "V" general, 1992 (Box 100, Folder 1023)
    - Vaill, Amanda, 1994 (Box 100, Folder 1024)
      Includes photocopies of the Murphy's correspondence with Picasso and some of Picasso's drawings thought to be Sara Murphy
    - "W" general, 1976 January 29 (Box 100, Folder 1025)
    - "Y" general, 1975 October 19 (Box 100, Folder 1026)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1974 April 22, undated (Box 100, Folder 1027)
  - Diaries and Notebooks
    - "My Adventures", 1927 (Box 101, Folder 1028)
    - Red leather diary, 1928 (Box 101, Folder 1029)
    - "Adventures in Montana", 1931 (Box 101, Folder 1030)
    - "Our Second's [sic] Year's Adventures in Montana", 1931 (Box 101, Folder 1031)
    - Diary, 1932-1935 (Box 101, Folder 1032)
    - "Our Trip to Spain in the Weatherbird ", 1933 (Box 101, Folder 1033)
    - Diary, 1948 (Box 101, Folder 1034)
    - Small red leather notebook with transcriptions of poems and Ruth Allen's phone number, undated (Box 101, Folder 1035)
  - Other Papers
    - Sketchbook "Messina, Italy", undated (Box 102, Folder 1036)
    - Childhood artwork by Honoria Donnelly, undated (Box 102, Folder 1037)
    - Sketch for Honoria Donnelly by Hale Walker, 1925 (Box 102, Folder 1038)
    - Scrapbook with "collections of movie cut-out pictures of my favorites -- fashions of my time when I was around fourteen years old", 1932
    - The Rosemary Question Mark, 1933-1934 (Box 102, Folder 1039-1041)
    - Invitation, wedding certificate, and other papers relating to marriage of Honoria Donnelly and John O. L. Shelton, 1943-1997 (Box 102, Folder 1042)
    - Printing plate for "Mrs. William M. Donnelly" calling card, circa 1950 (Box 102, Folder 1043)
    - John Charles Baoth Donnelly baby hair, 1952 (Box 102, Folder 1044)
    - Wiborg family history "Drammensfamilien Wiborg" by Terje Gudbrandson (published in Oslo by Reidar Wiborg Jr.), 1971 (Box 102, Folder 1045)
  - Writings
    - Sara & Gerald
      - Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 103, Folder 1046-1048)
      - "Constitution of the Authors Guild", undated (Box 103, Folder 1049)
      - Research notes, before 1982 (Box 103, Folder 1050-1054)
      - Research notes, before 1982 (Box 104, Folder 1055-1056)
      - Drafts, before 1982 (Box 104, Folder 1057-1060)
      - Cover art, before 1982
      - Publicity, 1982-1984 (Box 104, Folder 1061-1065)
      - Reviews, 1982-1983 (Box 105, Folder 1066-1068)
      - Fan mail, 1984-1990 (Box 105, Folder 1069)
    - The Villa America Cookbook
      - Research notes and drafts, undated (Box 105, Folder 1070)
  - Printed Materials
    - Articles About Sara and Gerald Murphy
      - Agee, William C. "Gerald Murphy, Painter: Recent Discoveries, New Observations" and William M. Donnelly "On Finding A Gerald Murphy." Arts Magazine, 1985 May (Box 106, Folder 1071)
      - Ball, Aimee Lee. "Bye-Bye Brigadoon." New York Magazine, 1990 March 12 (Box 106, Folder 1072)
      - Barry, Naomi. "Sailing Away with Leger." House & Garden, 1984 February (Box 106, Folder 1073)
      - Berendt, John. "The Espadrille." Esquire, 1986 July (Box 106, Folder 1074)
      - Bonetti, David. "Swedish Ballet in Paris." San Francisco Examiner, 1996 June 24 (Box 106, Folder 1075)
      - Braff, Phyllis. The Surrealists and their Friends on Eastern Long Island at Mid-Century (East Hampton, N.Y.: Guild Hall of East Hampton), 1996 (Box 106, Folder 1076)
      - City Lights Books. "Great Literary Encounters" calendar with photograph of Ernest Hemingway, Fraulein Glaser, John Dos Passos, and Gerald Murphy skiing on the cover, 1981
      - Corn, Wanda M. "Identity, Modernism, and the American Artist after World War I." Studies in the History of Art, 1991 (Box 106, Folder 1077)
      - Dupont, Pepita. "Sur la Plage, a Cap-d'Antibes, Sara, le Coup de Foudre Secret" Paris Match, 1996 October 10 (Box 106, Folder 1078)
      - Epstein, Joseph. "In Concord With Luxe." Wall Street Journal, 2002 April 3 (Box 106, Folder 1079)
      - Emery, Noemie. "Mythical Georgetown." The Weekly Standard, 2003 December 8 (Box 106, Folder 1080)
      - Eyman, Scott. "Living Well with the Best of Friends." Accent, The Palm Beach Post, 1992 March 29 (Box 106, Folder 1081)
      - Fiori, Pamela. "150 Years of Hopes and Dreams." Town & Country, 1996 October (Box 106, Folder 1082-1083)
      - Flanagan, Barbara. "An Art Orbit of Celebrities." The Minneapolis Star, 1975 November 13 (Box 106, Folder 1084)
      - "Fun Worshipers." Avenue, 1992 January (Box 106, Folder 1085)
      - Ghilaga, Tess. "Lost Horizons." Hamptons, 2000 May 26-June 1
      - Goodman, Wendy. "Growing Up with the Lost Generation." House & Garden, 1992 February (Box 106, Folder 1086-1087)
      - Guillet, Jean-Luc. "Les Americains au Cap." Terre Provencale, 1997 September-October (Box 106, Folder 1088)
      - Kimmelman, Michael. "A Face in the Gallery of Picasso's Muses is Given a Name." The New York Times, 1994 April 21 (Box 106, Folder 1089)
      - Leahy, Molly. "The Murphys." The World of Hibernia, 1997 Spring (Box 106, Folder 1090)
      - Lilli, Monica. "Alla Ricera della Bellezza." Elle, Italy, 1999 October (Box 106, Folder 1091)
      - Lopez, Pamela. "Mark of Success." Vogue, 1996 March (Box 106, Folder 1092)
      - Markus, Julia. "Palmy Days Along the Riviera." The New York Times Magazine, 1994 March 6
      - Owens, Mitchell." Eyre de Lanux: Remembering an Innovator of Modern Design." Architectural Digest, 1997 November (Box 106, Folder 1093)
      - Purgavie, Dermot. "My Mother Was Picasso's Secret Love." You, 1995 March 12 (Box 106, Folder 1094)
      - Pylkkänen, Jussi. "Picasso's Classical Muse." Christie's, 2002 June 25 (Box 106, Folder 1095)
      - Robinson, Jeffrey. "Villa America." Gourmet, 1989 July (Box 106, Folder 1096)
      - Rubin, William. "The Pipes of Pan: Picasso's Aborted Love Song to Sara Murphy." Artnews, 1994 May (Box 106, Folder 1097)
      - Rubin, William. "The Pipes of Pan: Picasso's Aborted Love Song to Sara Murphy." Artnews, 1994 May (Box 107, Folder 1098)
      - Suzy. "East to West, It's Good Cheer for New Homes." The Miami Herald, 1990 February 27 (Box 107, Folder 1099)
      - Tomkins, Calvin. "Picasso's True Lies." The New Yorker, 1996 May 13 (Box 107, Folder 1100)
      - Tomkins, Calvin. "Takes." The New Yorker, 2000 April 10 (Box 107, Folder 1101)
      - Walsh, Sharon and Judd Tully. "Harriman's Art Is Put Up for Auction." The Washington Post, 1995 February 23 (Box 107, Folder 1102)
      - Wayne, Kenneth. Impressions of the Riviera: Monet, Renoir, Matisse and Their Contemporaries. Augusta, Maine: Portland Museum of Art., 1998 (Box 107, Folder 1103)
      - Winkfield, Trevor. "From a Friend of Gerald Murphy." Modern Painters New York, 1998 May (Box 107, Folder 1104)
    - Ephemera from Exhibitions of Gerald Murphy's Artwork
      - Salon des Independents, Grand Palais, Paris, photocopies of newspaper clippings from 1924, undated (Box 107, Folder 1105)
      - The Brooklyn Museum and High Museum of Art Atlanta, "The Machine Age in America: 1918-1941", 1986-1987 (Box 107, Folder 1106)